# **PIYUSH GARG**

(Associate Company Secretary)

M. No. A55197

2 year of experience in the field of Statutory & Regulatory Compliances

Personal Information:		
Name:	Piyush Garg	
Date of Birth:	30 <sup>th</sup> April, 1994	
Marital Status:	Unmarried	
Address:	D-36, 1st Floor, West Jyoti Nagar, Shahdara, New Delhi-110094	
Mobile:	+91 9818939060	
Email:	piyushgarg369@gmail.com	

#### **Executive Summary:**

A Competent professional with 2 year of experience in Company Secretarial Profile, having a reputation of analytical approach, taking quick decisions and timely compliances. Proficient in handling the Statutory Compliances under Companies Act, 2013, SEBI (LODR) Regulations, 2015, SEBI (SAST) Regulations, 2011, SEBI (PIT) Regulations, 2015, and other corporate and allied laws. Recently worked as the Company Secretary of BHASIN GROUP. The group is into Real Estate, Hotel Business, having its projects in Noida, Greater Noida etc. The Group Consists of 35 Companies including LLP (approx.)

# **Professional Objective:**

To carve a niche for myself in the corporate world as a well known Company Secretary, explore myself to my best and to contribute my learnings and skills towards the overall growth of an organization.

Key Strengths:		
Managerial ability		
Presentable and pleasant personality		
Keen mind to learn new things		
Good Judgmental Quality		
Love to work beyond boundaries		

#### **Major Achievements:**

All India Second Highest Marks in CS Professional 2nd Group.

15 Days' Specialized Training, prescribed by ICSI at Registrar of Companies, NCT of Delhi and Haryana.

#### **Work Experience:**

#### **Stock Exchange& SEBI:**

- Applying for ISIN by Corporate Action (Public and Private Companies)
- Quarterly, Half yearly, Annually and other event-based compliances under SEBI (LODR)
- Compliances under SEBI (SAST) & SEBI (Insider Trading) Regulations
- Handled Preferential Issue of Warrants as well as Equity Shares
- Liasoning with NSDL, CDSL, BSE, NSE & RTA (Alankit Assignments Ltd.) of Company

# **Companies Act and Secretarial Standard:**

- Well versed with the provisions of the Companies Act, 2013 and amendment thereto
- Convening Board Meeting, Various Committee Meetings and General Meeting (AGM and EGM)
- Pre and Post Compliances of Board/General/Committees meeting
- Drafting of Notices, Detailed Agenda and Minutes for Board and their Committees and General Meetings.
- Preparation of Director's Report, Corporate Governance Report and Annual Report.
- Incorporation of OPC under Companies Act, 2013.
- Shifting of Registered Office of Various group Companies.
- Change of name clause, object clause and accordingly alteration of MOA, AOA etc.
- Appointment, Reappointment, Resignation as well as Change in Statutory Auditors of Various Companies.

- Appointment, Reappointment, Resignation of Director including Managing Director and Independent Director and Nominee Director and KMP (CEO, CFO CS) of various Companies.
- Increase in Authorized Share Capital of the Company and alteration in MOA accordingly.
- Further Issue of Paid up Capital through Right Issue, Private Placement, Preferential Allotment, Sweat Equity
- Online payment of Stamp Duty for fresh issue of Equity Shares to Department of Revenue.
- Deposit Return (One Time and Annual) under Section 73 to 76 of Companies Act, 2013 (DPT-3)
- Applying for DSC of Directors and KMP.
- Application for Surrender of DIN.
- Filing of e-form DIR-3 KYC and DIR-3 KYC WEB Based.
- Annual filing and event-based filing with MCA 21 (Private, Public and Listed Companies)
- Transfer of unclaimed and unpaid dividend to IEPF and filing thereof.
- Transfer of Shares on which dividend remain unpaid and unclaimed to IEPF authority.
- Preparation of documents relating to Transfer of Shares, Transmission of Shares and Split of Shares.
- Issue of Duplicate Share Certificate.
- Filed e-form INC-22A of various Companies.
- Ben Filing and MSME Filing
- .Allotment of Shares
- Inspection and their evaluation of various Companies.
- Maintaining and Updating Statutory Registers as per Companies Act, 2013
- Charge Management including Creation, Modification and Satisfaction of Charge.
- Drafting of various resolutions as per the requirement of various departments.
- Coordinate with Statutory Auditors, Internal Auditors and Secretarial Auditors.

#### **Limited Liability Partnership Act, 2008:**

- Incorporation of LLP
- Annual Compliances of LLP (Form 8 & Form 11)
- Change in Object and Designated Partner of LLP
- Strike off of LLP

# Other Allied Laws & Acts:

- Registration & renewal of Trademarks
- Drafting and finalization of agreements for Assignment process of trademarks
- Application for Import License under Rule 27 of Legal Metrology (Packaged and Commodities) Rules, 2011.
- Application for Alcohol to be kept at home above permissible limit, with Excise, Entertainment and Luxury Tax Department (Form L30)
- Filing FLA Return and Annual Performance Report (APR) under FEMA

# Legal:

- Drafting and finalization of Share Purchase Agreement, NDA, GPA, Affidavits, Indemnity Bonds, Assignment Agreements and other Commercial agreements, Lease Deed and Pledge Agreement
- Appearance before Courts and Quasi-Judicial Body as a Authorized Representative
- Coordinating with various advocates & counselors, Legal Firms
- Preparation and monitoring of MIS on legal cases

# Managerial:

- Designing and implementing systems, procedures and manuals for the preparation and maintenance of statutory compliances with time and accuracy norms
- Updating Directors, KMP and senior management on various legal & regulatory amendments.
- To ensure registration under various laws and obtain required certificates, approvals and clearances
- Coordination with CFO and financial team in order to ensure smooth compliances
- Recruiting, mentoring and training executives in department to deliver quality services

Organizations:				
Name of the Organization	Designation	Duration		
Bhasin Infotech and Infrastructure Private	<b>Company Secretary</b>	April 2019- till date		
Limited				
JHS Svendgaard Laboratories Limited	Asst. Company Secretary	August 2018 - November 2018		
(Listed at BSE & NSE)				
JHS Svendgaard Retail Ventures Private Limited	<b>Company Secretary</b>	December 2018 - April 2019		
TI F '4 CI C HIC CVENDO A ADD I ADODATODIEC LIMITED (1 C ) '1' 4 1				

The Equity Share of JHS SVENDGAARD LABORATORIES LIMITED (the Company) is listed on two stock exchanges BSE and NSE.

The Company is engaged in the business of manufacturing, import and export of oral care products like toothpaste, toothbrush, mouthwash etc. The factory of the Company is situated at Kala-Amb, Himachal Pradesh.

A key responsibility that I undertake includes the Compliances under Companies Act, 2013, SAST Regulations, PIT Regulations, SEBI (LODR) Regulations with the Stock Exchanges.

Working in co-ordination with the group of Directors and KMP and Senior Management e.g. Managing Director, CEO, CFO, Vice President, and heads of other departments, involved in day today affairs of the Company. The responsibilities further extend to appearance before various courts and Quasi-Judicial Body and liasoning with advocates, legal firms.

# SANJAY GROVER & ASSOCIATES (Practicing Company Secretaries Firm) CS Management Trainee June, 2016 – February, 2018 (21 Month Training)

Completed 15 Months Company Secretary–Management Training with Sanjay Grover and Associates well reputed Practising Firm situated at B-88, 1<sup>st</sup> Floor, Defence Colony, New Delhi-110024.

#### Work experience at the time of training:

- Incorporation of various Companies (Subsidiary of Foreign Company and Private and OPC)
- Shifting of registered office from one state to another state.
- Compounding of offence under section 441 of Companies Act, 2013.
- Preparation of documents related to condonation of delay.
- Assisted in Secretarial Audit, Share Capital Reconciliation Audit and Corporate Governance Audit.
- Preparation of various reports (Scrutinizer Report, Director Report, Annual Report)
- Liaison with Government Officials of MCA, ROC, RD, OL, RTA.
- Attending AGM/EGM of various Companies as a team member of Scrutinizer.
- 3 month Experience in REPL Group (Retainership Company of Sanjay Grover & Associates)
- One month experience in ROC Office.

Education:		
LLB	Pursuing (2 <sup>nd</sup> Year Complete)	CCS University
Certified CSR Professional	2020	ICSI
M.Com	2018	IGNOU
Company Secretary	Dec, 2017 (Cleared Exams)	ICSI (All India 2 <sup>nd</sup> highest marks in CS Prof.
	May, 2018(Got Membership)	Module II)
B.Com	2014	Sai Nath University
XII	2011	CBSE
X	2009	CBSE

# **Computer Proficiency:**

Conversant with MS Word, Excel, Power Point and working knowledge of Internet and related application.

Linguistic Proficiency & Hobbies:		
English	Hindi	
Travelling	Listening to Music Adventure Sports	

Date: 2020
Place: New Delhi
Sd/Piyush Garg